Amit Pawar

amitpawar5252@gmail.com 8600468603 Pune, Maharashtra

Summary

Throughout my 5+ years career as a full stack software developer, I have focused on developing scalable and well-documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects independently. Excited about the prospect of joining a product-driven company.

Experience

Software Developer

Amdocs • Pune, Maharashtra

11/2021 - Present

- 1. Worked on building and enhancing User identity, Account and subscription management product handling around 20+ million users.
- 2. Worked closely with the product team to identify and fix critical bugs, adding new functionalities and enhance user journey. Wrote clean, scalable and well-documented code in ReactJS and Spring boot to achieve functional requirements.
- 3. Worked closely with DevOps team in activities like tech upgrade, creating and enhancing Jenkins jobs, build deployments etc.

Assistant Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services • Trivandrum, Kerala 04/2019 - 10/2021

- 1. Worked with business users and operations teams to understand business needs and address production questions.
- 2. Analysed requirements and designed, developed and implemented Document Management System and Customer Communication Management System for a banking domain with help of Newgen products Omnidocs and OmniOMS.
- 3. Wrote a code in Java to build custom wrapper REST APIs which can be consumed by other platforms. Built a utility for batch processing using Java which reads xml files and spools data into Oracle DB.

Angular Developer

TMK Computers • Pune, Maharashtra 05/2018 - 03/2019

- 1. Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- 2. Built database and table structures following MySQL architecture methodology for web applications.
- 3. Built web services to perform CRUD operations using Laravel framework.
- 4. Wrote and tested code in Angular 6 to develop responsive frontend.

Skills

Java, Spring framework, Spring boot, ReactJS, Angular, Git, CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker

Education

BSc Computer Science

Tuljaram Chaturchand College, Baramati • Baramati, Maharashtra 04/2018